so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist today I want to share
with you how you can spread ideas more
effectively and more specifically how
you can take an idea turn it into a
story and then tell the story in a
really powerful way so that other people
are engaged they want to take up the
challenges that the story brings out in
them put that puts them out onto a life
journey that changes themselves in their
communities in the book that I want to
review today that shows you how to do
this is this one resonate by Nancy dort
and it's the subtitle as prep present
visual stories that transform audiences
so here's the thing about Nancy Duarte
is she is one of the people who helped
like shape the way that people creating
TED Talks have made their talks so that
they could be successful and what she is
done in this book and throughout her
work with a helping people create
PowerPoint presentations or slide decks
that transform the world as she has
studied the underlying structure the
story structure of really great speeches
so she looked at the I have a dream
speech by Martin Luther King and she
looked at steve jobs speech when he was
announcing the creation of the iphone
you know things like this where people
would give a talk and the talk would be
transformative for the audience and the
ideas in the talk which is spread across
society and change the world and so what
she does in resonate is she walks you
through the storytelling techniques so
just as a little example when you were
creating a presentation one of the
things you can do to engage your
audience is you can start the talk off
with a discussion of like right here
this is where the world is today and
where the world tis today is not the
best that it could be there are problems
with it you know so for Martin Luther
King there's a world where people are
living in poverty and they're being
oppressed and their voices aren't being
heard that sort of thing and then you
can go from that to this up here this is
the world as it could be I have a dream
of my children and your children being
respected for what's in the core of
their character not the color of their
so you see how that juxtaposition of
world as today world as it could be
creates an emotional tension that people
get engaged in they get called to action
they get pulled into the story find
themselves being a part of it and then
want to go on the journey to see where
the story ends now when Nancy Duarte xin
resonate if she takes insights like that
and she helps people understand how to
tell powerful stories which for those of
us who want to create positive social
change in the world we really need to be
good at telling stories so that's what
this is all about she also looks at the
research that people like Joseph
Campbell have done Joseph Campbell the
person who documented the different
mythology systems around the world and
found what was common to them or looking
at the architecture of stories and
really good pieces of drama like the
Star Wars movies or et where there's a
structure to the story and there's a way
that the characters are formed there's a
way that you're drawn and to relate to
the protagonist and how you go on the
journey with them and you go through
your own transformation as you're
viewing this story and then it becomes
part of your life and you take it with
you so insights like this or shared in
resonate in a very practical visual way
so for example you can see that the book
is constructed around images so that you
can really see how like this is the
journey of the audience she has these
great visual representations to show you
how to take people on that journey in
your storytelling so if you have a story
you need to tell if you have an idea
that you want to spread you want to get
better at telling it this is the book
for you resonate by Nancy Duarte so go
get your copy today and make the world a
better place